What's this? A view?
這是什麼？只拍了風景？
Isn't this the same beach we're at?
這不就是我們現在所在的海灘嗎？
Looks like it.
好像是
Shinpei?
慎平？
Or Mio? Or someone else?
還是泠？或是其他的人呢？
Anyways, I'll just talk assuming you're Shinpei.
隨便，我就當作是慎平吧
If you are watching this, I'm not in this world any more.
當你看到這個影片的時候 就表示我已經不在這個世上了
You just wanted to say that line.
你就是想說一次這種老套的臺詞吧
How did you know?
被發現了？
Well, I know myself.
畢竟是自己啊
Come here. Let's both be in it.
真是的，你過來這裡一起拍吧
What...
什…
Over here?
站這裡嗎？
A little to the left.
稍微往左一點？
Ushio and her shadow?
-潮和影子在一起？ -走過頭了
Perfect.
很好
What are you doing?
你到底在做什麼？
Shinpei.
慎平
Listen carefully.
接下來我說的這些話，你要仔細聽
Only my shadow and I can unlock this cell phone.
能夠解鎖這支手機的 只有我和我的影子
That means my shadow must be with you now.
所以現在在你身邊的應該是我的影子
By the way, can you tell which one is me?
-對了，能認出來哪個是我嗎？
Hey! I'm talking here!
-喂，現在是我在說話啦
Left? Or right?
-是左邊那個？ -是我吧
They get along.
-關係真好啊，她們兩個 -是我吧
-That doesn't matter! -That doesn't matter.
-隨便哪個都行
-We are both me.
-因為都是我嘛
I'm sure you know by now,
我想你應該已經知道了
but that one is not evil like the other shadows.
她和其他的影子不同 不是壞人，所以放心吧
She's on your side, I promise!
她是站在你這邊的，我可以保證
My shadow will explain the details,
具體情況可以問問我的影子
but I wanted to tell you directly, too.
但我也想用我自己的語言 直接為你留下訊息
That's why I'm doing this video.
所以錄下這個影片給你
What should I start with?
該從什麼地方說起呢？
Right. It all began with Shiori.
好，事情的開端是詩織…
It's more than a look-alike!
才不只是長得很像的人
I think someone followed me home from school today, too.
今天我放學回家，感覺有人在跟著我
Is it a stalker? Be careful. Should I tell Totsumura?
是可疑的人物吧？
Totsumura can't help! I know it's that girl.
凸村靠得住嗎？我很肯定就是那個人
Sis, is this the medicine for Dad's athlete's foot?
姐姐，是這個嗎？爸爸治腳氣的藥
Yeah, that's it.
沒錯，就是那個
You're not listening! I should charge you double!
都不認真聽我說 信不信我加倍收你們的錢？
What is it? What's the problem?
怎麼了？在說什麼呢？
Never mind then. Thanks for coming.
算了，多謝惠顧
Mio, look.
泠，看那個
Who's there?
你是誰？
Wait!
等一下
Did I lose her? Huh?
逃掉了啊
Shadow...
影子…
It's more than a look-alike!
才不只是長得很像…
A shadow?
影子？
Yeah, we'll look into your story about the look-alike.
對，關於你說的那個長得很像的人 我會去調查一下
So you decided to believe me?
真的嗎？你終於肯相信我了？
Yes, so don't worry anymore.
對，所以別再擔心了
Omotohama trash collection event is now concluded!
萬年青海灘撿垃圾大賽到此結束
Thanks to you, the beach is clean for its big opening tomorrow.
在大家的努力之下 海灘變得乾淨起來
We will burn the collected trash at the Omiokuri event.
今天大家收集的垃圾 將會在下次的御海送上燒掉
Okay everyone, see you at the summer festival on the 24th.
那麼各位 我們在24日的夏日慶典上再會吧
KOFUNE
（小舟）
Rock, paper, scissors, shoot!
-剪刀、石頭、布，再一次！
Yay! I go first!
好耶，我先洗
Hey, sis.
對了，姐姐
Will Shinpei be back this summer?
不知道今年夏天小慎會不會回來
Yeah right, I know you like him.
別這麼說嘛，你明明就喜歡他
You like Shinpei.
姐姐你明明就很喜歡小慎
-What are you saying? -Stop it...
什…
Shinpei... I wonder what he's doing now?
慎平現在在做什麼呢？
Hi.
你回來啦
Mio!
泠！
What are you?
你到底是什麼人？
Did you follow us from Omotohama?
從萬年青海灘跟著我過來的嗎？
I'm Ushio Kofune. I just came home to my own house!
我是小舟潮，回自己家有什麼問題？
Then... why were you hiding?
那你為什麼躲在浴室裡？
That's because you were with Mio.
因為你和泠回來了啊
You are...
你…
-Do you know about shadows?
-知道影子的事嗎？
-You're the shadow.
-你就是影子吧 -你才是影子吧
Wait a second. If shadows really exist...
等一下，如果影子是真實存在的話…
Shiori's shadow is somewhere on the island too!
-那詩織的影子應該也在島上的某處
I have a bad feeling.
我有不好的預感
Didn't Shiori say she first saw her shadow on Mt. Takanosu?
詩織說她第一次見到影子 是在鷹之巢山對吧？
Shouldn't we check it out?
你不覺得有必要調查一下那裡嗎？
I guess. I'll deal with you later.
好吧，你的事情之後再處理
Why are you following me?
你為什麼要跟過來？
You're the one who's following.
是你跟著我吧
I promised Shiori I'd look into this so that she can stop worrying.
我答應過詩織會調查影子的事 要她不用擔心
Make any strange moves, and I'll finish you!
你要是有任何一點可疑的舉動 我就會解決掉你
Got it?
明白了嗎？
There are no leads.
沒什麼線索啊
I'm out of time today. I need to hike down before it gets dark.
今天只能到這裡了，得在天黑前下山
Come here.
快來這裡
KEEP OUT
（禁止進入）
Look. There's a trail ahead.
看，這前面有條路
This totally makes me want to go in.
看到這樣的牌子 是不是特別想進去？
I know, right!
我懂
Oh, this must be the old clinic Sou's family had.
對了，這裡不就是 窗他家的舊病房嗎？
HISHIGATA CLINIC
（菱形醫院）
Rumor says that this old clinic is haunted.
以前就傳言這裡鬧鬼
Everyone is afraid of it, so they stay away.
島上的人覺得害怕，誰都不敢靠近
So scary! I hate ghosts!
好可怕，唯有鬼會讓我害怕
You too?
你也是啊？
Yet, you seem eager to go inside. Aren't you scared?
但你怎麼還一直往前走啊？ 要進去嗎？你不怕？
I'm scared, but I have a feeling...
也不是不怕，可是該怎麼說呢？
PRESCRIPTIONS
（櫃台）
like I've been here before.
感覺自己好像來過這裡
Who is it! Who's there?
是誰？有人在那裡？
That's the shadow? It's got my face!
這是影子？那張臉是我
Watch out!
危險
What was that...
剛才那個是什麼…
Let go! Damn! What is this?
放開我，可惡，這是什麼啊？
Damn.
可惡
What's happening? It wasn't my leg that was stabbed!
怎麼會這樣？我的腿明明沒被刺中啊
Oh, I get it now.
原來是這樣
It's the shadow's weakness.
原來如此，影子的弱點是…
I know. My body clearly felt it.
我知道了，我剛才用身體搞清楚了
I am not human.
我不是人類
You're not getting away!
別想逃
My true body is the flat shadow.
我的本體是平面的影子
This image of the body...
立體是…
is a device to protect the true body.
為了保護本體的武器
You...
你…
What was that?
剛剛那是怎麼回事？
I...
我…
That was amazing, super cool!
太厲害了吧，你也太帥了
I know, right?
對吧？
Wow! It healed.
好厲害，癒合了
I copied the data of your right foot.
我只拍了右腿的數據
So it's like data?
像是“數據”的感覺嗎？
I don't know how to put it, but it's like that.
我也不太會形容，大概就是那種感覺
But this copied data will probably disappear.
不過我想，這些複製的數據 會慢慢消失的
If the original is deleted, the copy becomes the original.
只有消除原型 複製品才能變成原型本人
Deleted? Does that mean killed?
消除？也就是殺掉嗎？
Will you disappear unless I die?
我要是不死，你就會消失嗎？
I just have that feeling in my head.
不清楚，但我就是這麼覺得
Normally, I guess I'm supposed to kill you.
正常來說，我必須殺了你
So that's why people say you die once you see your shadow.
怎麼會這樣？看到影子就會死 原來是這麼回事
Shiori is in danger.
詩織有危險
We have to do something about it.
我們兩個要想辦法救她
So you must be with my shadow now.
所以現在在你身邊的應該是我的影子
What will Shinpei think when he finds out that I am fake?
知道我是冒牌貨後 慎平會怎麼想呢？
-By the way, can you tell which one is me?
-對了，能認出來哪個是我嗎？
-Hey! I'm talking here!
-喂，現在是我在說話啦
That doesn't matter.
隨便哪個都行
We are both me.
因為都是我嘛
Ushioh. You two tried to save Shiori.
潮，你們本來想靠你們兩人 拯救詩織嗎？
I remember. I remember now!
我想起來了，我全都想起來了
Your memory...
你的記憶…
Has it come back?
恢復了嗎？
It's not just my memory. My power came back too.
不只是記憶，我的力量也恢復了
Power?
力量？
I want you to see the truth of the end of my life.
我想讓你們看我死前的真相
I'll recreate it from my memory data.
我試試看從我的記憶數據中 找出過去的影像，重現出來
Let's go to the private beach on July 21st!
走吧，去7月21日的私人海灘
This place...
這裡是…
Hey, Shinpei, look!
喂，慎平，看那邊
I'm so glad it's sunny!
是晴天啊，太好了
Right!
是啊
It is the perfect weather to study.
真是學習的好天氣啊
Perfect weather for swimming!
是適合海水浴的好天氣啦
Hey, Shiori! I heard you can't swim. How lame!
喂，詩織，你還不會游泳啊，好丟臉
Hamaji, you can't even eat mushrooms!
濱路你不也是一樣 到現在都不敢吃香菇吧
I can't eat mushrooms, but that's not lame!
不敢吃香菇又不遜，我無所謂啦
Is that...
那是…
No doubt. That's us from the 21st.
沒錯，就是21日的我們
Oh, I need to stop them! Hey!
不行，要阻止他們，喂，大家
It's pointless.
沒用的
This is just an image from the past. We are just watching a recording.
這是過去的影像 我們只是在看著錄像而已
We can't touch or speak to them.
無法觸碰他們，也無法與他們對話
Right, Ushioh?
對吧？潮
Damn.
可惡
Where were you at this time?
這個時候你在哪裡？
Come with me.
跟我來
One, two, three, four, five.
-一、二、三、四、五…
Have I put on some weight?
我的肚子好像真的有點突出來了
Don't say that. It's been bothering me.
真是的，別說啦，會很在意的
This is where you copied the swimsuit.
就是這時候複製了泳衣嗎？
Just watch.
繼續看下去吧
I can't get near Shiori like this.
但這樣我也無法接近詩織啊
I have an idea. Can you turn into this?
我有個好主意，你能變成這個嗎？
Sure.
可以
Okay. Well?
嘿咻
Perfect!
完美
I turned into the shell necklace and Ushio wore me.
我變身為貝殼項鍊，被戴在潮的身上
I took off the real necklace and put it in my pool bag.
真正的項鍊被摘下來 放到游泳包裡了
Hey, Mio.
泠
How can I be a good swimmer like you? I want to learn!
怎漾才能像你遊得那麼好啊？ 我也想學會游泳
You will! Let's do a swimming lesson today!
一定能學會的，今天就來上游泳課吧
Who wants to learn how to swim?
想要學會游泳嗎？
Me!
想
Shiori.
詩織…
That's the spirit!
很有氣勢嘛
I'll protect you, no matter what.
無論發生什麼事，我一定會保護你的
What's wrong?
怎麼了？
Akari says she pooped.
朱里說她便便出來了
Uh-oh.
哎呀
I didn't! I just need to go, it's coming out!
才不是，是快要出來了，快憋不住了
You want me to take you?
要和姐姐一起去廁所嗎？
Hurry!
-快點，快點啦 -沒關係，我帶她去吧
Shiori?
詩織？
What's wrong?
怎麼了嗎？
Shiori's gone.
詩織不見了
Look! There!
快看，哥哥，在那邊
Ushio, it's in the water! I can feel a shadow!
潮，在海裡，有影子的氣息
Tokiko, take Akari! Come, Sou!
朱鷺子，朱里拜託你了，窗
Sure!
好
Shinpei, did you see what happened to Shiori?
慎平，你看到了嗎？ 詩織怎麼會突然跑到海裡去？
Ah, no.
沒看到
Sorry, this is a memory.
抱歉，這是記憶
I can't recreate what no one saw.
誰都沒看到的場景是無法再現的
Stay back!
別過來
Don't come! Leave this to me!
你們不能過來，交給我
Sis.
姐姐？
Don't be a fool, Ushio! What are you thinking?
潮你這笨蛋，你在想什麼啊？
Hang in there, Shiori.
等著我，詩織
I see it!
找到了
It's Shiori's shadow!
詩織的影子…
Here I go.
好，上吧
Leave this to me.
好，交給我
Wait.
等等
I chose her. You can't take her.
我已經選中她了，不許帶走
I can't move.
動不了
I am so close to the surface,
差一點就可以到達水面了啊
and Shiori is going to die.
詩織會死的
Go! Hurry, take Shiori!
走，快點，去救詩織
Ushio!
潮
Dummy!
笨蛋
Don't stop! Just go!
你在發什麼呆？快走啊！
How am I ever going to return this kind of favor?
這麼大的人情，要我怎麼還啊？
Go,
快走…
me...
我…
Stop.
等等
I told you to stop.
我說等等
I feel someone coming. You lucked out.
他們靠近了，算你走運
Shiori.
詩織…
Sis!
姐姐！
Ushio!
潮！
I'm sorry, Ushio. I couldn't save Shiori.
對不起，潮，我沒能保護好詩織
I will kill the shadows with Shinpei.
我會和慎平一起幹掉影子的
I will save everyone at the summer festival on the 24th.
把大家從24日的夏日慶典中救出來
Is that enough to pay you back for this?
這樣是不是就能還你一點人情了？
Yes, of course that's enough.
對，可以的，一定可以
She pretended to lose consciousness and took Shiori's place.
假裝昏倒，欺騙大家 就這樣取代了詩織嗎？
Yes.
是啊
I can't stand that monster.
我絕對不會原諒那傢伙的，混蛋
I want to kill it with my own hands.
我現在就想親手殺了她
Yes. We killed it already.
是啊，已經殺掉了
Hey! How can you be so calm?
喂，你怎麼還能這麼冷靜？
But...
但…
I should have done it.
本來應該要由我來動手的
Shinpei. I'm sorry.
慎平，對不起
Who should do what now?
你說誰本來該動手做什麼？
Found you.
找到你了
Hey, Ushioh. Isn't this just an image?
喂，潮，這是影像吧？
You said they can't touch or talk to us.
無法觸碰，也無法對話吧
What's this? It's not in my memory.
怎麼會這樣？我沒有這樣的記憶
This is bad. End this, Ushioh!
感覺不太妙，快結束影像，潮
It took me a long time to find you after that.
在那之後，我就一直在找你
I won't let you get away this time.
你逃不掉了
Shinpei, look at your arm.
慎平，你的手臂…
That's where it grabbed me.
是被那傢伙抓住時留下的痕跡
Translated by James Burns
字幕翻譯：李珮嘉